{
    "id": "e23f70366bf94176af056135195bd88e",
    "title": "Expect, Hope and Wait",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She is ……………… a promotion.",
            "description": "Before a noun we use hope for or wait for. Expect is used without for.",
            "answers": [
                "waiting",
                "hoping",
                "expecting"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "32c4e30e0b0a4bf98abf8918c71029c9"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am ………………… Maria to come in the evening.",
            "description": "If we expect something to happen we have a good reason to believe that it will happen.",
            "answers": [
                "expecting",
                "hoping",
                "waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "35c34d8dbbf242558f08cf647712b098"
        },
        {
            "question": "I am ………………… to hear from her.",
            "description": "All three of these verbs are possible before a to-infinitive with somewhat similar meanings.  ",
            "answers": [
                "waiting",
                "hoping",
                "expecting",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "7f9e3053cd80440ea30c124034136d4e"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ……………….. to get a bike for his birthday.",
            "description": "Either hopes or expects is possible here.",
            "answers": [
                "hopes",
                "expects",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "25439b9501f145cd8ba0ebcb1579940e"
        },
        {
            "question": "I have been ………………. for her for hours.",
            "description": "We wait when somebody or something is late.",
            "answers": [
                "waiting",
                "hoping",
                "expecting"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "89f245be32744f9db7581e7ace7fbf51"
        },
        {
            "question": "She can’t ………………… for her birthday.",
            "description": "Can’t wait shows impatience.",
            "answers": [
                "wait",
                "hope",
                "expect"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e4b4af7212d1468e91e69d1e809f94b4"
        },
        {
            "question": "We are ………………….. rain soon.",
            "description": "Before a noun we use hope for or wait for. Expect is used without for.",
            "answers": [
                "expecting",
                "hoping",
                "waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "d34cb21ac2844506a98beda4a0ebd9fb"
        },
        {
            "question": "We are ………………… to get good rains this year.",
            "description": "Before a to-infinitive, all of the above are possible. ",
            "answers": [
                "hoping",
                "expecting",
                "waiting",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "915b861bc6bb43e3bcd57e6e62188b5c"
        },
        {
            "question": "She is quite shy. I ………………….. her to be smarter.",
            "description": "Before object + infinitive we use hope for or wait for. Expect is used without for.",
            "answers": [
                "expected",
                "hoped",
                "waited"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "4169f5830cf540f48df0cc9f2de75510"
        },
        {
            "question": "Employees are ………………… to start work at 9 o’clock.",
            "description": "Expect is often used with object + infinitive to talk about people’s duties. Passive forms of this structure are also common.",
            "answers": [
                "expected",
                "hoped",
                "waited"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "49bcce1fb359451cb01f34fb2cd243f9"
        },
        {
            "question": "We are …………………. that you can come and stay with us.",
            "description": "Progressive forms of expect are not normally used before a that-clause.",
            "answers": [
                "hoping",
                "expecting",
                "waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "f606543cf3574098a344d1fca2873791"
        },
        {
            "question": "We ………………. to hear from her today.",
            "description": "Before a to-infinitive simple and continuous forms of hope and expect are used with very similar meanings.",
            "answers": [
                "hope",
                "expect",
                "are hoping",
                "are expecting",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "correct": 4,
            "id": "761ca9fb835d4f449e3e82a9b4fbc0e0"
        }
    ]
}